SR. PRODUCT-MARKETING MANAGER Summary

Energetic Product Manager with over 10 years of expereince working in with hotels, cars, cruise, as well as receptors. Areas of experties include Caribbean, Latin America, Florida, Disney, and Universal.with [number] years of experience providing [service]. Areas of expertise include [skills].

Energetic manager of products with knowlegde across all themes(hotel, care, cruise) creating responsible for the overall strategy, commercial management and the development of JetBlue's vacation product and ancillary partnerships. The Manager oversees a team of Getaways product and business development managers, and the Getaways operations team. The Manager supports the Director JetBlue Getaways & Leisure Sales to ensure revenue goals are met and aligned with opportunities for long term strategic growth in product development.

The Manager enjoys working in a matrix environment across many different business units and levels and has the ability to influence without formal authority. The Manager collaborates with existing business partners and identifies new partners that will contribute and align with JetBlue's goals and revenue objectives within the focus market. The Manager enjoys working on a fast paced environment and is an effective leader whose personal values match JetBlue's values of Safety, Caring, Integrity, Fun and Passion.

Skills

PC Technology - Excel, Word, Access, Power Point, Project & Visio

Expertise in Booking Solutions; EzRez, Tech-7, GDS; Sabre; & Travelocity, Orbitz, Expedia Extranets

- · Contract negotiations
- Expert product knowledge with Domestic, Caribbean, Latin America, Car, Cruise, 3rd party receptors, Hotels.com, HotelBeds USA, Tourico

Trained in Dreamweaver MX 2004, knowledgeable on HTML, Adobe Acrobat and Photoshop Accomplishments

15 years experience negotiating contracts. overrides, coop marketing with hotels, tourist boards, CVB's

Experience

 $360\mbox{Pi}$ January 2004 to Current SR. PRODUCT-MARKETING MANAGER Hershey , PA

- Leading Internet Travel Company of Caribbean, Mexico, Latin America and Domestic travel packages Managed marketing strategy, tactics
 and execution of product, as well as the directing, marketing services, customer service and retail marketing for a company with \$5M in
 annual revenue and a \$1M marketing budget.
- Spearheaded strategic product planning, consumer research, sales/expense planning and reporting, as well as ROI and promotion analysis.
- Led a 15-person staff including 4 direct reports and outsourced creative personnel to develop web site, execute direct mail and e-mail acquisition marketing.
- Identified and evaluated marketing and product initiatives, strategies and programs through consumer research competitive analysis and internal metrics and management reporting.
- Key Achievement: Produced 30% to 45% increase in passenger volume year after year with a 5% increase in dollar share from 2004 to 2005 by repositioning company's marketing initiatives from offline to online.
- Drove product definition by customer needs with competitive analysis and market research, while balancing customer needs, company needs and technology capabilities within overall budget constraints.
- As project manager, led a cross-functional team defining product specifications for operations, technology, accounting and the call center.
- Established goals and created process maps to complete project on time and on budget.
- Generated \$1M+ in new product sales in 2 years by spearheading new product development and implementation.
- Fueled sales with \$50,000 in cooperative funding in 2 years by identifying new product and target segments.
- Created a promotional strategy by developing unique and exclusive promotions that acquired new customers while retaining old.
- Promotions included; Honeymoon in Paradise, Save Now & Later with Sunburst and Free Time in the Caribbean.
- Saved company \$30,000 by educating self on Google and Yahoo Adword knowledge.
- Managed and bid on key words while creating Ads.
- Analyzed resulting data utilizing Google Analytics and Web Trends.
- Achieved a 20%+ ROIs and 5% redemption rates for developing marketing acquisition plans including promotions for market segments such as Tweens and 50+, with e-mail campaigns, Adwords and 3rd party vendors such as Booking Buddy, Smarter Travel, Booking Whiz and more.
- Communicated product status to entire company including executive team with key issues in reference to engineering, design, PR and

- customer support.
- Made key decisions on products from product launch, mark up, content, customer awareness, market and trend analysis.
- Managed new product launches for Latin America and the USA by creating marketing plans, meeting with technology, web design, customer support, operations and accounting.

Microsoft Corporation January 2001 to January 2003 SR. MARKETING MANAGER Arlington , $\rm VA$

- Project Manager for new product launches communicating needs and wants to internal staff as well as web development, technology, customer service, sales and accounting.
- Saved company \$30,000 by creating a billing process that met the needs of internal and external customers.
- Also reviewed all bills, financials, P&Ls and media schedules.
- Saved compay \$1M from 2001 2003 by conducting monthly audits on marketing intiatives and billing.
- Verified that media ran, created process if media did not run.
- Generated \$50,000 worth of cooperative marketing funds from hotels, airlines, car companies and tourist boards.
- Saved company \$10,000 a year by negotiating fax and e-mail contracts.
- Increased e-mail list by 20% (approximately 5,000+) by implementing exclusive promotions such as "Caribbean Ice".
- Managed all coop marketing agreements and media schedules; once in house, reviewed profit and loss, run dates and ad size.

Bickford Senior Living January 1997 to January 2003 Moline, IL

- A wholly owned wholesale travel company the provides travel arangements to travel agents and consumer direct.
- Oversaw the daily operations of a \$10M marketing budget that facilitated ads to all consumer and trade advertising including print, radio and online advertising.

360Pi January 1997 to January 2001 SR. PRODUCT - MARKETING MANAGER Pittsburgh

- Responsible for managing the day-to-day activities of hotels, resorts, tourist boards, CVB's, airlines, car rental companies.
- Also managed accounting, customer service, inventory and education of product, competitiveness and marketing.
- Key Achievements Account Manager and internal advocate for assigned suppliers such as Sandals, SuperClubs, Club Med and Hertz
- Earned company \$1.5M in cooperative advertising as well as override incentives with hotels, tourist boards, airlines and car companies.
- Contributed to 5% increase in passenger volume year over year, through market analysis, relationship management and training.
- Drove key decisions from development of product, to consumer facing advertising.
- Analyzed product on consumer and trade facing advertising, reported findings to Director and Vice President of Product.

Education and Training

Keystone College 1988 Associate of Arts (AA) : Travel and Tourism City , State , USA ave Bachelor of Science (BS) City , State Skills

Microsoft Office, Sabre, knowledgeable with dynamic packaging system such as Tech - 7, SwitchFly. Expert knowledge with hotels, tourist boards, CVB's in the Caribbean, Latin American, USA, as well as ancillary product Car, Cruise, Off site airport parking.